Jean Marzollo Papers 2006.0181
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Jean Marzollo Papers
undated, 1993-2001.
2006.0181
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
3.0 Linear feet
The collection contains books illustrated by Marzollo and promotional puzzles and games based on the popular series I Spy written by several prominent authors including Walter Wick.
Marzollo, Jean.
Biography
Jean Marzollo was born in Manchester, CT. She is the author and author-illustrator of over 100 books and a former teacher. Marzollo graduated from the University of Connecticut in 1964 and received an M.A. in Teaching from Harvard University. She taught high school in Arlington, MA, and for Harvard's Upward Bound program. For twenty years she was the editor of Scholastic's early childhood magazine Let's Find Out. She is best known for her I Spy series with Walter Wick, as well as the Shanna's First Readers series. She has also adapted and illustrated a number of stories from the Bible and Greek and Roman mythology.
Additional information about the author is available from her website.
General note
Donated Published Works:
Adams, Patricia and Jean Marzollo; ill. Moores, Jeff. The Helping Hands Handbook, New York: Random House, 1992.
Marzollo, Dan; ill. Yoshimoto, Ward. I Spy a Circus, New York: Scholastic, 2003.
Marzollo, Dan; ill. Yoshimoto, Ward. I Spy a Rocketship, New York: Scholastic, 2004.
Marzollo, Dan; ill. Yoshimoto, Ward. I Spy a Runaway Robot, New York: Scholastic, 2003.
Marzollo, Dan; ill. Yoshimoto, Ward. I Spy Pirate Treasure, New York: Scholastic, 2003.
Marzollo, Jean. Chicken Pox Strikes Again, New York: Scholastic, 1990.
Marzollo, Jean. Do You Love Me, Harvey Burns?, New York: Dial, 1983.
Marzollo, Jean. Jonah and the Whale (and the Worm), New York: Little, Brown & Co., 2004.
Marzollo, Jean. Ma soeur est une commère, New York: Scholastic, 1991.
Marzollo, Jean. My Sister the Blabbermouth, New York: Scholastic, 1990.
Marzollo, Jean. Roses Are pink and You Stink!, New York: Scholastic, 1990.
Marzollo, Jean. The Best Present Ever!, New York: Scholastic, 1989.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Björkman, Steve. In 1492, New York: Scholastic, 1991.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Björkman, Steve. En 1492 [Spanish edition], New York: Scholastic, 1993.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Björkman, Steve. In 1776, New York: Scholastic, 1994.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Blake, R.J. The Baby Unicorn, New York: Scholastic, 1987.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Carson, Carol Devine. The Rebus Treasury, New York: Dial, 1986.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. MacDonald, Suse. I Love You, New York: Scholastic, 2000.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. MacDonald, Suse. I See a Star, New York: Scholastic, 2002.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Meddaugh, Susan. Blue Sun Ben, New York: Dial, 1984.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Meddaugh, Susan. Red Sun Girl, New York: Dial, 1983.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Meddaugh, Susan. Ruthie’s Rude Friends, New York: Dial, 1984.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Moffatt, Judith. Ah! L’eau!, New York: Scholastic, 1996.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Moffatt, Judith. I Am a Leaf!, New York: Scholastic, 1998.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Moffatt, Judith. I Am a Nature Reader!, New York: Dial, 1998.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Moffatt, Judith. I Am a Rock, New York: Scholastic, 1998.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Moffatt, Judith. I Am a Star, New York: Scholastic, 2000.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Moffatt, Judith. I Am an Apple, New York: Scholastic, 1997.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Moffatt, Judith. I Am an Apple, New York: Scholastic Big Books, 1997.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Moffatt, Judith. I Am Planet Earth, New York: Scholastic, 2001.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Moffatt, Judith. I Am Fire, New York: Scholastic, 1996.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Moffatt, Judith. I Am Snow, New York: Scholastic, 1998.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Moffatt, Judith. I Am Water, New York: Scholastic, 1996.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Moffatt, Judith. I Am Water, New York: Scholastic, 1999.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Moffatt, Judith. I’m a Caterpillar, New York: Scholastic, 1997.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Moffatt, Judith. I’m a Seal, New York: Scholastic Big Books, 1996.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Moffatt, Judith. I’m a Seed, New York: Scholastic, 1996.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Moffatt, Judith. Moi, le feu…, New York: Scholastic, 1996.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Pinkney, J. Brian. Feliz Cumpleaños, Martin Luther King!, New York: Scholastic, 1993.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Regan, Laura. Mama Mama, n.p.: Harper Collins, 1999.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Regan, Laura. Papa Papa, n.p.: Harper Collins, 2000.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Regan, Laura. Sun Song, n.p.: Harper Collins, 1995.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Rogers, Jacqueline. Once Upon a Springtime, New York: Scholastic, 1997.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Rogers, Jacqueline. Snow Angel, New York: Scholastic, 1995.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Schweninger, Ann. The Teddy Bear Book, New York: Dial, 1989.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Sheehan, Nancy. How Kids Grow, New York: Scholastic, 1998.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Sims, Blanche. Cannonball Chris, New York: Random House, 1987.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Sims, Blanche. Red Ribbon Rosie, New York: Random House, 1988.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Sims, Blanche. Slam Dunk Saturday, New York: Random House, 1994.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Sims, Blanche. Soccer Sam, New York: Random House, 1987.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Sims, Blanche. The Pizza Pie Slugger, New York: Random House, 1989.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Takabayashi, Mari. Do You Know New?, n.p.: Harper Collins, 1998.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Thornton, Shelley. Baxter’s Bad Day, New York: Scholastic, 1983.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Thornton, Shelley. Doll House Christmas, New York: Scholastic, 1983.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Thornton, Shelley. Papa Bear’s Party, New York: Scholastic, 1982.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Thornton, Shelley. Three Little Kittens, New York: Scholastic, 1985.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Trivas, Irene. Fathers and Toddlers, New York: Harper Collins, 1994.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Trivas, Irene. My First Book of Biographies: Great Men and Women Every Child Should Know, New York: Scholastic, 1994.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Trivas, Irene. Soccer Cousins, New York: Scholastic, 1997.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Trivas, Irene. Supertot: Creative Learning Activities for Children One to Three and Sympathetic Advice for Their Parents, New York: Harper & Row, 1977.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Trivas, Irene. The New Kindergarten: Full Day, Child Centered, Academic, New York: Harper & Row, 1987.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. True, Kelley. Baseball Brothers, New York: Scholastic, 1999.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. True, Kelley. Basketball Buddies, New York: Scholastic, 1998.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. True, Kelley. Football Friends, New York: Scholastic, 1997.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. True, Kelley. Hockey Hero, New York: Scholastic, 1998.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. True, Kelley. Une partie de football, New York: Scholastic, 2001.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Wick, Walter. I Spy: 4 Picture Riddle Books, New York: Scholastic, n.d..
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Wick, Walter. I Spy: A Book of Picture Riddles, New York: Scholastic Big Books, 1992.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Wick, Walter. I Spy a Candy Cane, New York: Scholastic, 2004.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Wick, Walter. I Spy a Funny Frog, New York: Scholastic, 1997.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Wick, Walter. I Spy a Penguin, New York: Scholastic, 2005.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Wick, Walter. I Spy a Scary Monster, New York: Scholastic, 2004.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Wick, Walter. I Spy Christmas! [Korean edition], New York: Scholastic Big Books, 2004.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Wick, Walter. I Spy Lightning in the Sky, New York: Scholastic, 2005.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Wick, Walter. I Spy Little Learning Box, New York: Scholastic, 2003.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Wick, Walter. I Spy Santa Claus, New York: Scholastic, 2005.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Wick, Walter. I Spy Ultimate Challenger!, New York: Scholastic, 2005.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Wilhelm, Hans. Halloween Cats, New York: Scholastic, 1992.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Wilhelm, Hans. Valentine Cats, New York: Scholastic, 1996.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Williams, Kent. Getting Your Period: A Book About Menstruation, New York: Dial, 1989.
Marzollo, Jean; ill. Wolff, Ashley. Home Sweet Home, New York: Harper Collins, 1997.
Marzollo, Jean and Claudio Marzollo; ill. Rose, David S. Jed’s Junior Space Patrol, New York: Dial, 1982.
Marzollo, Jean and Claudio Marzollo; ill. Sis, Peter. Jed and the Space Bandits, New York: Dial, 1987.
Scope and Content
The Jean Marzollo Papers contains promotional versions of a number of Marzollo's works, as well as puzzles and games inspired from the I Spy book series.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by format.
Series I: Books ( 1993-2003 )
Series II: Puzzles, Games and Toys ( undated, 1996-2001 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to children's literature and associated artwork. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Jean Marzollo in 2006.
Illustrator.; Wick, Walter.; Author.; Books.; CD-ROMs.; Educational games.; Northeast Children's Literature Collection.; Puzzles.; Toys.
- Series I: Books, 1993-2003
  - En 1492, 1993 (Box 1)
    General note
    [Originally published in 1991. Illustrated by Steve Bjorkman; translated by Aida E. Marcuse.]
  - Feliz Cumpleanos, Martin Luther King, 1993 (Box 1)
    [Illustrated by J. Brian Pinkney.]
  - I Spy: a book of picture riddles, 1993 (Box 1)
    [Photographs by Walter Wick; design by Carol Devine Carson.]
  - I'm a seed, 1997 (Box 1)
    [Originally published in 1996. Illustrated by Judith Moffatt.]
  - I am water, 1999 (Box 1)
  - I am an apple, 2000 (Box 1)
    [Originally published in 1997. Illustrated by Judith Moffatt.]
  - I Spy Little Learning Box, 2003 (Box 1)
    [Text by Jean Marzollo, photographs by Walter Wick. Contains I Spy Little Book, 1997; I Spy Little Numbers, 1999; and I Spy Little Letters, 2000.]
- Series II: Puzzles, Games and Toys, undated, 1996-2001
  - I Spy Memory Game, 1996 (Box 1)
    [Based on I Spy Spooky Night, 1996, text by Jean Marzollo, photographs by Walter Wick; Game by Martine Redman.]
  - I Spy Preschool Game, 1998 (Box 1)
    [Based on I Spy Little Book, 1997, text by Jean Marzollo, 1997, photographs by Walter Wick, 1992.]
  - I Spy collection, 1998 (Box 1)
    - I Spy Mystery, 1993
    - I Spy CD-ROM, 1997
    - I Spy Monster Workshop puzzle, 1998
  - I Spy 1000 piece puzzle: Bulletin Board, 2001 (Box 1)
    [Based on I Spy Mystery, 1993, text by Jean Marzollo, photographs by Walter Wick.]
  - I Spy 1000 piece puzzle: Marbles, 2001 (Box 1)
  - I Spy keychain, 2002 (Box 1)
  - I Spy viewmaster discs, 2003 (Box 1)